Leon Zhang

Montreal, Quebec • 514-998-2475 • leonzhang51@gmail.com • LinkedIn.com/in/leon-zhang-design/ • Portfolio: https://leonzhang51.github.io/

UX DESIGNER

UX designer-developer (hybrid) focused on both customer and business needs. Champions client ideas and produces solutions for development and product design that meet revenue goals.

- "How it Works" Focus: Adept at conceptualizing design ideas and bringing them to life with a focus on analysis, business requirements, and optimizing user experience.
- **Innovative Thinker:** Sees the big picture and provides creative, unique solutions for customers, with the goal of engaging users and earning their repeat visits.
- **Business Results:** Successful history of creating apps, landing pages, and new components that significantly increase traffic and revenue.

Core Technologies:

UX Skills: Usability Testing, Rapid Prototyping and Wireframes, Interaction Design, User Research (interviews, surveys), Experience Strategy, Experience Map, User Journeys, Storyboards, Task Flows, Heuristic Evaluation, Information Architecture, UI Design/Graphic Design

UX Tools: Axure, Figma, Adobe XD, Sketch App

Languages: HTML 5, CSS3, JS, PHP, MYSQL, React JS, Angular, Jquery, Bootstrap

EDUCATIONAL BACKGROUND

Bachelor of Science in Telecommunications Engineering University of Electronic Science and Technology of China

AEC Conception et programmation de sites Web - 2018 to 2019

College de Maisonneuve, Quebec, Canada

EXPERIENCE HIGHLIGHTS

CHEFAIDE, Montreal, Quebec, Canada

PRODUCT DESIGNER, 6/2019 - Present

Technologies: UI Design, Rapid Prototyping and Wireframes, HTML, JS, CSS, Bootstrap, Information Architecture, PHP / MYSQL

Designed and built websites using UI and UX principles to optimize user experience. Researched and gathered data – surveys, heatmapping, usability testing - in collaboration with business analysts and researchers, to inform the design process. Developed mock-ups, storyboards, process flows, sitemaps, and prototypes to illustrate site behavior and requirements.

- Designed a cross-platform mobile education app that is predicted to benefit more than 60 percent of teachers in Guinea and Senegal, in West Africa.
- Under development: Creating a mobile app for Sireta OnDemand and Sireta Travel that estimates indicate will result in new employment opportunities as well as \$500K in increased company revenue.

Leon(lie) Zhang

Page Two

L3 Studio, Montreal, Canada

UX DESIGNER, 2/2014 – 4/2018

Technologies: Usability Testing, Rapid Prototyping and Wireframes, Interaction Design, User Research, User Journeys, Storyboards, Information Architecture, Business Design

Redesigned client websites, translating concepts and business requirements into user flows, wireframes, mockups, and prototypes to create an intuitive user experience.

- Redesigned an online grocery store website, which resulted in a 46 percent increase in new user registrations and a 51 percent increase in repeat visits/purchases – successfully increasing revenue by 120 percent.
- Added a new business model component to an online craft store resulting in 100 percent growth of new users and a 300 percent increase in revenue in the first year.
- Applied Google Lighthouse recommendations to a client's website redesign project, which successfully improved load speed by 40 percent.
- Boosted registration of new users by 40 percent with the introduction of a new display-result model that incorporated more meaningful, precise, and friendly content.
- Optimized the user journey on a client's mobile app based on a "simplify" philosophy, which increased customer satisfaction by 70 percent.

EARLY EXPERIENCE

MultiCaf, Montreal, Quebec

WEB DESIGNER / INTERN, November-December 2019

Technologies: HTML, CSS, Bootstrap 4

Designed websites, mobile apps, and new landing pages from concept through deployment. Incorporated responsive design and a mobile-first approach and strategy, with a focus on balance between function and aesthetic design.

Marie Claire Laval, Montreal, Quebec

STORE MANAGER, 2008 to 2013

Managed daily operations and inventory for a retail store, provided excellent customer service, and marketing the store and its special promotional events via popular mobile apps.